Guide to the Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
24-04-3369
5.0 cubic ft.
Reprints and pamphets.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Veterinary reprints and pamphlets dating from 1865-1950. Many authored by faculty of the New York state College of Veterinary Medicine at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Veterinary reprints and pamphlets dating from 1865-1950. Many authored by faculty of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine at Cornell University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine--Faculty.
Subjects:
Veterinary Medicine--Study and teaching.; Veterinary literature.
Form and Genre Terms:
Reprints.; Pamphlets.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Most of the collection was transferred from the Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library.Additional reprints were separated from the Veranus Moore papers and the Myron Fincher papers.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Arranged alphabetically by author. Government publications without an explicit author are filed at the end.
CONTAINER LIST
- No Author
  - "Koch's tuberculosis conclusions." American Veterinary Review, September 1901. (Box 1)
- A
  - Abel, John. "Chemistry in relation to biology and medicine with especial reference to insulin and other hormones." Reprinted from Science, October 1927. (Box 1)
  - Abel, Mary Hinman. "Sugar as Food." U.S. Department of Agriculture Farmer's Bulletin No. 93, 1899. (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, E. B. "Administrative Control of Glanders." Department of Health of the City of New York, Reprint No. 16, April 1914. (Box 1)
  - Adelmann, Howard B. "The Fence." Reprinted from The American Scholar, Winter 1943-1944. (Box 1)
  - Alvord, Henry E. "Statistics of the dairy: Compiled from the United States census for 1890, and from other reliable sources with explanatory notes." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 11, 1896. (Box 1)
  - Alvord, Henry E. and R. A. Pearson. "The Milk Supply of Two Hundred Cities and Towns." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 46, 1903. (Box 1)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association. "Nomina Anatomica Veterinaria." 1923. (Box 1)
  - American Public Health Association. " Resolutions on the death of Dr. Wyatt Johnston." 1903 (Box 1)
  - Armsby, Henry Prentiss and J. August Fries. "Energy values of red clover hay and Maize Meal: investigations with the respiration calorimeter, in cooperation with the Pennsylvania State College agricultural experiment station." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 74, 1905. (Box 1)
  - ________ and J. August Fries. "The Available Energy of Red Clover Hay." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 101, 8 January 1908 (Box 1)
  - Arup, Johannes. "Viehversicherungen in Danemark." VIII. Internationaler Tierarztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Asdell, S. A. ""The future of the science of animal breeding." Reprinted from The Scientific Monthly, June 1947 (Box 1)
  - ________. "Research in animal physiology and genetics in Great Britain." Reprinted from Record of Proceedings of the American Society of Animal Production, 1930. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Sterility and delayed breeding in dairy cattle." Cornell Extension Bulletin, 737, June 1948. (Box 1)
  - ________ and G.W. Salisbury. "The rate at which spermatogenesis occurs in the rabbit. Reprinted from The Anatomical Record, June 1941. (Box 1)
  - Atwater, W.O. and Chas D. Woods. "The Chemical Composition of American Food Materials." U.S. Department of Agriculture Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin, No. 28, 1896. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Foods: Nutritive Value and Cost." U.S. Department of Agriculture Farmers' Bulletin, No. 23, 1894. (Box 1)
  - Atwood, George E. and George Hassletine. "Undulant Fever in Ware County, GA." Reprinted from Public Health Reports, 13 June 1930. (Box 1)
  - Aujeszky, Aladar. "Die Bedeutung der saurefesten, tuberelbacillenahnlichen stabchen bei der beurteilung der untersuchunern auf tuberkulose." VIII Internationaler Tierarztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Ayers, Henry S. "The present status of the pasteurization of milk." U. S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 342, 8 January 1916. (Box 1)
- B
  - Babes, V. "Rapport sur les recherches plus recentes concernant la transmission des maladies des animaux domestiques chez l'homme." VIII. Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Badger, L.F. "Psittacosis outbreak in a department store." U.S. Public Health Service Public Health Reports, Reprint No. 1386, 1930. (Box 1)
  - Baker, Donald W. "Gastrointestinal parasitisms of calves in New York State." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College, 1947-1948. (Box 1)
  - ________. "A new system of anthelmintic control for gastro-intestinal parasites of ruminants." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1939. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Parasitic gastro-enteritis of calves." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, October 1937 (Box 1)
  - ________. "Parasitic hazards encountered in southern and western raised calves and lambs in New York. Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1941. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Physaloptera in New York State dogs. Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1941. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Some mites injurious to domestic animals and man encountered recently by New York State veterinarians." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, July 1942. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Species of eimerian coccidia found in New York State cattle." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College, 1937-1938. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Studies of parasites of sheep." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College, 1936-1937. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Survival of worm parasite infection on New York State pastures." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1939. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Ticks found in New York State." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1946. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Yeast as an adjunct to the anthelmintic treatment of advances cases of trichostrongylosis in calves." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1941. (Box 1)
  - ________ and John W. Britton. "Egg counting for use in the diagnosis of equine strongylosis " Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College, 1937-1938. (Box 1)
  - ________ and R.C. Klussendorf. "Comparative sensitivity of common types of antigen." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, October 1930. (Box 1)
  - ________ and R, C. Klussendforf. "Precautions in shipping material for diagnosis." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April1930. (Box 1)
  - ________ and Herbert T. Dalmat. "Key to the larvae of botflies and warble flies infesting domestic animals in New York State." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College, 1941-1942. (Box 1)
  - ________ and Veranus Moore. "Undulant fever." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1930. (Box 1)
  - ________ and S.K. Nelson. "Dicrocoelium dendriticum infections in N.Y. State cattle." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, July 1943. (Box 1)
  - ________, G.W. Salisbury and J.W. Britton."Control of Equine Strongylosis, Part 1." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, July 1939. (Box 1)
  - ________ and W.S. Stone. "A syudy of spirrillum ovis infection in a group of ewes maintained under observation for two successive lambing seaseons." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1939 (Box 1)
  - ________ and J. P Willman. Control of Worm Parasites in Market Lambs." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, July 1940. (Box 1)
  - ________ and J. P Willman. "Controlling internal parasites of sheep." Cornell Extension Bulletin, no 407, April 1939." (Box 1)
  - Baker, J.C. and L.L. Van Slyke. "The Determination of the Keeping Quality of Milk." From Technical Bulletin, No. 72, June 1919. (Box 1)
  - ________. and L.L. Van Slyke. "A Method for the preliminary detection of abnormal milks, No. 71, June 1919. (Box 1)
  - ________. and L.L. Van Slyke. "The reaction of milk in relation to the presence of blood cells and of specific bacterial infections of the udder." Technical Bulletin, No. 80, July 1920. (Box 1)
  - Baldelli, Bruno. "Studio di un caso di ossificazione renale nel bovino." Reprinted from Rivista de Biologia, 1943. (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Edward, R. "The Ophthalmo-Tuberculin diagnotic test." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 14 December 1907. (Box 1)
  - ________ and P.A. Levene. "The action of proteolytic enzymes on bacterial toxins." Reprinted from Journal of Medical Research, Vol. VI, July 1901. (Box 1)
  - _________. "The problem of immunity in tuberculosis." Reprinted from Transactions of the Sixth International Congress on Tuberculosis, 28 September and 5 October 1908. (Box 1)
  - Bancroft, Wilder D. and J.E. Rutzler. "Reversible coagulation in living tissue." Reprinted from the proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 17, April 1931. (Box 1)
  - Barach, Alvan, L. "The therapeutic use of oxygen in heart disease." Reprinted from Annals of Internal Medicine, Vol. 5, October 1931. (Box 1)
  - Barker, J.R. "Sterility." National Veterinary Medical Association of Great Britain and Ireland Annual Meeting, August 1923. (Box 1)
  - Barker, Lewellys, F. "On the study of anatomy." Reprinted from The Johns Hopkins Hospital Bulletin, Vol. XII, April-June 1901. (Box 1)
  - ________. "The unveiling of the cell." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 1 March 1902. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Progress of Neurology." Reprinted from The Philadelphia Medical Journal, 1899. (Box 1)
  - Barnes, Arlie R. and Merritt B. Whitten. "Study of the R-T interval in myocardial infarction." Reprinted from The American Heart Journal, December 1929. (Box 1)
  - Barrett Mfg Co. "The Standardization of Disinfectants, with a Note on the Real-Walker Method of Controlling Cost Efficiency." 1912. (Box 1)
  - Bassett, S.H., Evelyn Holt and F.O. Santos. "The Influence of meat upon physical efficiency." Reprinted from The American Journal of Physiology, May 1922. (Box 1)
  - Beach, J.R. "The effect of feeding bacillus acidophilus, lactose, dry skim milk, or whole milk on the hydrogen ion concentration of the contents of the ceca of chickens." Hilgardia: A Journal of Agricultural Science published by the California agricultural experiment station, October 1925. (Box 1)
  - _______. and D.E. Davis. "The influence of feeding lactose or dry skim milk on artificial infection of chicks with eimeria avium." Hilgardia: a journal of agricultural science published by the California agricultural experiment station, October 1925. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Infectious bronchitis of fowls." Reprinted from Journal of American Veterinary Medical Association, February 1926. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Observations on the occurrence of fowl cholera in California." Reprinted from Poultry Science, August - September 1922. (Box 1)
  - _______. "Suggestions to poultrymen concerning chicken-pox." University of California College of Agriculture Berkeley Circular No. 145, December 1915. (Box 1)
  - _______ and J.C. Corl. "Studies in the control of avian coccidiosis." Reprinted from Poultry Science, Vol. 4, February-March, 1925. (Box 1)
  - _______. and D.E. Davis. "Coccidiosis of chickens." University of California College of Agriculture, Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 300, October 1926. (Box 1)
  - Beal, F.E.L. "Some common birds: in their relation to agriculture." From the U.S. Department of Agriculture Farmers' Bulletin, No. 54, 1897. (Box 1)
  - Bela, Kovacsy. "Az istalloza es legeltetes elettni es allattenyesztesi szempontbol." From VIII. Nemzetkozi Allatorvosi Kongresszus Budapesten, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Beck, G.H. and G.W. Salisbury. "Rapid methods for estimating the quality of bull semen." Reprinted from Journal of Dairy Science, June 1943. (Box 1)
  - Bendixen, H.C. and Erik Blom. "Investigations on brucellosis in the bovine male, with special regard to spread of the disease by artificial insemination." Reprinted from The Veterinary Journal, October 1947. (Box 1)
  - Benner, James W. "Hog cholera vaccination breaks and their prevention." Reprinted from the Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, April 1927. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Hog cholera in the young pig." Reprinted from the Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, May 1928. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Immunizing young pigs against hog cholera." Reprinted from the New York State Veterinary College Annual Report, 1926-1927. (Box 1)
  - Bergey, D.H. "Common Colds: Their cause, prevention, and treatment." Reprinted from the Philadelphia Medical Journal, 19 May 1900. (Box 1)
  - Beringer, Kurt. "Uber ein neues, auf das extrapyramidal-motorische system wirkendes alkaloid (banisterin)." Reprinted from Der Nervenarzt, ca. 1949. (Box 1)
  - Berry, John M. "A Comparison of the phagocytic action of leukocytes in amphibia and mammalia." Reprinted from the Transactions of the Twentieth Annual Meetings of the American Microscopical Society held at Toledo, Ohio, 5-7 August 1897. (Box 1)
  - Bessis, M. and J. Caroll. "Anticorps anti-mulets incomplets et bloquants chez la jument mere de muleton icterique." Reprinted from Comte Rendus des seances de la Societe de biologie." 26 April 1947. (Box 1)
  - Beyer, Karl H. "New concept of competitive inhibition of renal tubular excretion of penicillin." Reprinted from Science, 24 January 1947. (Box 1)
  - Biggs, Hermann M. "Milk-Borne Septic Sore Throat: A New Health Problem." New York State Department of Health, 1915. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Preventive Medicine in the City of New York." The address in public medicine delivered at the 65th annual meeting of the British medical association, in Montreal, Canada, September 1897. (Box 1)
  - Bing, Jens and N.O. Christensen. "The connection between plasma cells and the occurrence of hyperglobulinemia in horses and cattle." Reprinted from Acta Medica Scandinavica, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Birch, R.R. "Bang abortion disease in relation to interherd transfer of cattle." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, April, 1930. (Box 1)
  - ________. "A bang's disease survey of a representative dairy township." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University for the year 1932-33. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Handling of Bang's Disease - A report of progress." Reprinted from the proceedings of the Forty-Fourth Meeting of the United States Live Stock Sanitary Association, December 1940. (Box 1)
  - ________."Hog cholera." Cornell Reading Course for the Farm: Livestock Series, Lesson 150, October 1919. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Hog cholera: Its economic importance and prevention." Reprinted from the Scientific Monthly, May 1918. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Garbage feeding, and the care of garbage fed swine." Reprinted from the 1918 Report of the New York State Veterinary College. (Box 1)
  - ________. Natural and artificial immunity to Bang's Disease." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University for the year 1936-1937. (Box 1)
  - ________. "The nature and economic importance of Bang's Disease of cattle." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University for the year 1931-32. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Some principles underlying official regulations for the control of Bang's Disease." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1932. (Box 1)
  - ________. "A study of hog cholera transmission." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York Veterinary College, 1913-1914. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Technique of drawing blood samples from cattle for the agglutination test." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, April 1926. (Box 1)
  - ________. and H.L. Gilman. "Handling Bang Abortion Diseases; a program for the veterinary practitioner." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University, 1927-1928. (Box 1)
  - ________. and H.L. Gilman. "The agglutination test as an aid in handling bang abortion disease." Reprinted from the 1929 Annual report of the state veterinary college. (Box 1)
  - ________. and H.L. Gilman. "Bang abortion disease in cattle." Cornell extension bulletin published by the New York State college of agriculture at Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, Bulletin 137, April 1926. (Box 1)
  - ________. and H.L. Gilman. "The pathogenicity for cattle of brucella strains isolated from cases of undulant fever in man." Reprinted from the Journal of Infectious Diseases, January-February, 1935. (Box 1)
  - ________ and H.L.Gilman. "Some notes and data concerning the resistance conferred by calfhood exposure to Bang's Disease." Annual Report of the State Veterinary College, ca. 1933. (Box 1)
  - ________ and Robert Stone. "Calfhood vaccination against Bang's Disease." Reprinted from the Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University for the year 1940-41. (Box 1)
  - Bissell, William G. "Formaldehyde Gas." Read before the Buffalo Academy of Medicine, 15 January 1901. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Municipal water-supplies and their examination." Reprinted from The Philadelphia Medical Journal, 30 August 1902. (Box 1)
  - Bitting, A.W. "Bovine tuberculosis in Indiana." Purdue University Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin, No. 63, December 1896. (Box 1)
  - Blanchard R. "Substances toxiques produites par les parasites animaux." VIII. Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Blom, Erik. (1947): "Om spermaundersogelsesmetoder hos tyren (On methods of evaluating bull semen)." Reprinted from Den Danske Dyrlaegeforening, 1948. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Spontaneous detachment of the galea capitis in spermia of bull and stallion." Reprinted from Skandinavisk Veterinartidskrift, 1946. (Box 1)
  - ________ and N.O. Christensen. "Undersogelser over sygelige tilstande i testis, epididymis og de accessoriske konskirtler hos tyren." 1946. (Box 1)
  - Bloom, Frank. "A clinical and pathological study of nephritis in dogs." Reprinted from the Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, December 1937. (Box 1)
  - Boger, William P. "Caronamide: A new enhancing agent for use in conjunction with penicillin therapy." Reprinted from Transactions and Studies of the College of Physicians of Philadelphia, December 1947. (Box 1)
  - ________. and Richard M. Baker. "A comparison of effect of caronamide and benzoic acid on penicillin plasma concentrations." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1947. (Box 1)
  - Bolton, B.M. "The bacteriolytic power of the blood serum of hogs." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 95, 12 March 1907. (Box 1)
  - Bongert, J. "Uber die art der infection bei der tuberkulose der haustiere." VIII. Internationaler Tieraztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905. (Box 1)
  - Bourne, Wesley. "What constitutes an efficient anesthesia service for hospitals." Reprinted from American College of Surgeons, March 1930. (Box 1)
  - Bovim, Arne. "En anatomisk undersokelse av hestens hofteledd - articulus cozae qui." Reprinted from Skandinavisk Veterinartidskrift, 1946. (Box 1)
  - Bowen, John T. "The cost of pasteurizing milk and cream." Bulletin of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, No. 85, 27 April 1914. (Box 1)
  - Branton, Cecil, R.W. Bratton, and G.W. Salisbury. "Total digestible nutrients and protein levels for dairy bulls used in artificial breeding." Reprinted from Journal of Diary Science, December 1947. (Box 1)
  - Bratton, R.W., et al. "Breeding behavior, spermatogenesis, and semen production of mature dairy bulls fed rations low in carotene." Reprinted from Journal of Diary Science, September 1948. (Box 1)
  - Braun, H. "Bakterienreinkulturen als Zellfamilien, 1. Mitteillung." Reprinted from Istanbul Seririyati, 1945. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Bakterienreinkulturen als Zellfamilien, 2. Mitteillung." Reprinted from Istanbul Seririyati, 1945. (Box 1)
  - ________ and Ö. Özek. "Über die Methodik der Untersuchung des Verwendungsstoffwechsels der Salmonella-Bakterien in synthetischen Nährlösungen für diagnostiche Zwecke." Reprinted from Istanbul Seririyati, 1945. (Box 1)
  - ________ and Ö. Özek. "Zur Vereinfachung der Diagnostik pathogener Darmbakterien." Reprinted from Istanbul Seririyati, 1946. (Box 1)
  - ________ and W. Silberstein. "Über Salmonella anatum." Reprinted from Istanbul Seririyati, 1944. (Box 1)
  - ________ and W. Silberstein. "Über Salmonella anatum, 2. Mitteillung" Reprinted from Istanbul Seririyati, 1944. (Box 1)
  - ________ and W. Silberstein. "Über Salmonella anatum, 3. Mitteillung." Reprinted from Istanbul Seririyati, 1944. (Box 1)
  - ________and W. Silberstein. "Über Salmonella eastbourne." Reprinted from Istanbul Seririyati, 1944. (Box 1)
  - Breed, Robert S. and James D. Brew. "The control of bacteria in market milk by direct microscopic examination." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 443, December, 1917. (Box 1)
  - Brewer, F.W. "Tuberculosis." Agricultural College of Utah Experiment Station, No. 41, 31 December 1895. (Box 1)
  - Brion, A. "Immunologie. - Sur le mécanisme de la'immunisation de la jument mulassière par son produit, et le passage des anticorps antimulet chez son muleton." Reprinted from Comptes Rendus des Séances de l'Académie des Sciences, May 1949. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Recherches sur la nature et la prophylaxie de l'ictère congénital des muletons." Reprinted from the proceedings of the Cinquieme Congrès International de Zootechnie, November 1949. (Box 1)
  - ________. "Sur l'ictère hémolytique du poulain nouveau-né." Reprinted from Revue de Médecine Vétérinaire, May 1949. (Box 1)
  - ________ and P. Goret. "Les Échanges immunitaires entre la mère et le foetus ou le nouveau-né. Conséquences et applications a l'étiologie et a la pathogénie de l'ictère hémolytique du muleton et du poulain." Reprinted from La Revue d'Immunologie, No. 5-6, 1949. (Box 1)
  - ________ and P. Goret. "Ictère hémolytique du muleton et du poulain." Reprinted from Revue de Médecine Vétérinaire, July 1949. (Box 1)
  - Britton, J.W., G.W. Salisbury and D.W. Baker. "Control of Equine Strongylosis, Part 3." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, July 1941. (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Paul B. "Two Milk-borne septic sore throat epidemics." Reprinted from American Journal of Public Health, September 1929. (Box 1)
  - Brower, A. Blaine and Walter M. Simpson. "Antianemic influence of desiccated whole hog stomach." Reprinted from The American Journal of the Medical Sciences, September 1931. (Box 1)
  - Brown, Charles W. and Kurt Peiser. "Keeping qualities of butter v. pasteurization and its influence, (contribution) a study of the factors which influence the resistance of lactic acid bacteria to heat." Michigan agricultural college experiment station division of bacteriology, Technical Bulletin, No. 30, October 1916. (Box 1)
  - Brunett, E.L. "Poultry Diseases." Reprinted from Cornell Extension Bulletin, Bulletin 337, November 1935 (Box 1)
  - Bryan, C.S "Mastitis control in the pen-type of dairy barn." Reprinted from Michigan Agricultural Experiment Station Quarterly Bulletin, November 1947. (Box 1)
  - Bugbee, Henry G. "Diverticulum of the ureter: a report of three cases." Reprinted from The Journal of Urology, August 1931. (Box 1)